Now that we learn how to post data in the last lecture,
imdi, son konudaki verileri nasl yaynlayacamz rendik.
let me also show you how to send a delete request to really wrap this up.
Ayrca silmek istemek iin silmek isteyip istemediinizi sana gstereceim.
Now just like for posting data, deleting here will not really delete any data from the backend, it just
imdi, burada gnderilen veriler silinirken silinen veriler gerekten arka taraftaki verileri silmeyecektir
mirrors back the data we send with our response we get basically.
ve temelde aldmz yantla gnderdiimiz verileri aynalamaktadr.
But still I can show you how you send it and you would use it on any other server in the same way.
Ama yine de sana nasl gnderdiini gsterebilirim ve onu baka bir sunucuda ayn ekilde kullanrsn.
Of course this server needs to accept the delete HTTP word for a given URL. Now the delete button is
Elbette sunucunun belirli bir HTP szcn silme ilemini kabul etmesi gerekiyor, imdi silme dmesinin tam
in the full post component,
deftere nakil bileeni var.
so there let's simply hook this button up to a method which handles this,
Dolaysyla bizi yalnzca bu ile uraan bir yntemle tekrar baladk.
I'll implement this method here,
Bu yntemi burada uygulayacam.
the deletePostHandler maybe, doesn't require any input and let's hook this method up here to onClick,
Kurun mesaj ileyicisi belki herhangi bir girdi gerektirmez ve bu yntemin tklamayla ikinizin bu silme
should execute this deletePostHandler method.
sonras ileyici veya Befort'u altrmas gerektiini umalm.
We already import axios in here,
Buraya zaten eriim ithal ediyoruz.
so now let's simply use axios and there we can use to delete method to issue delete requests. The
imdi sadece X-ists'i kullanalm ve silme taleplerini vermek iin Meffert'i silmek iin kullanabiliriz, daha sonra
delete method, whoops here
Meffert karanln silmek iin kullanabiliriz.
I need to add an equals sign.
Eittir iareti eklemeliyim.
The Delete method also takes a URL and we need to target a specific post with it. So we can simply
yayn onunla hedeflememiz gerekir, bylece size basite ulaabiliriz veya baka bir ekilde tek bir yayn getirmek iin kullanrz.
take the URL we used for fetching a single post,
Sil yntemi de bir metni alr ve belirli bir
it's the same URL we need for deleting and we don't pass any extra data because that URL already
Silinmesi iin ihtiyacnz olan L ile ayndr ve ekstra bir veri geirmiyoruz nk hcreniz zaten ihtiyacmz
contains all the data we need,
olan tm verileri iermektedir.
it targets a specific resource which should be deleted. I'll then chain then because again this is asynchronous,
Silinmesi ve sonra deitirilmesi gereken belirli bir kayna hedefler, nk yine bu zaman uyumsuzdur.
we will get some response and then I can log the response here to see what happened on the server.
Baz yant alacaz ve sonra sunucudaki olay grmek iin cevab buradan kilitleyeceim.
Let's now see these,
imdi onlar grelim.
let's load a post and click delete.
Bir yayn ykleyelim ve silmeyi tklayn.
And you can see, we successfully get back a response,
Ve siz de baaryla bir yant alabildiimizi grebilirsiniz.
we don't get actual data here,
Gerek verileri burada bulamyoruz.
that is just what the dummy backend returns to us here.
Bu sadece aptal geri dnd ve bizi buraya geri gnderiyor.
But the status code 200 indicates that it was successful,
Ancak devlet iki yzl ldrd, bunun baarl olduunu gsteriyor.
again it wasn't really deleted but I just want to show you that sending delete requests also is as simple
Yine de gerekten silinmedi ancak silmek isteyen isteklerin gnderilmesinin de bir yntem alveriinde bulunduunu
as exchanging one method, get or post, exchange it for delete and of course comparable methods are available
gstermek istediklerini silmek iin elleleme yntemini kullandklarn grdkten sonra sanki karlatrlabilir yntemler
for put, patch and so on.
var Port yamas vb.